<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

	
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Ben Hammersley&#039;s Dangerous Precedent</title>
	<link>https://benhammersley.com</link>
	<description>A blog about Cognitive Risk and Adaptive Futurism</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 22:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>https://benhammersley.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>https://benhammersley.com</wp:base_blog_url>

		<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[ben@benhammersley.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Ben Hammersley]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Ben]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Hammersley]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

				
	

<image>
	<url>https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/cropped-35625-Hammersley-Futures-Favicon-01-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Ben Hammersley&#039;s Dangerous Precedent</title>
	<link>https://benhammersley.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">155218423</site>
		<item>
		<title>Spectator Cockroaches, Sand, and the Social Facilitation of Skeuomorphs.</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2015/01/19/2015-1-19-socialfacilitationandbots/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 10:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2015/01/19/2015-1-19-socialfacilitationandbots/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">It was an experiment on cyclists in 1898 that first showed us how we might live with robots. It's a really interesting observation. Let me tell you about it.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">So.&nbsp;I love bots. Give me a pseudo-human interface, a smattering of natural language, and&nbsp;&nbsp;a computery-voice, and I'm all yours. This year I'm working on a <a href="/futures-thinking-with-complex-systems-ai-and-the-network">project to discover just how useful they can be</a>. With wearables, and systems like <a href="http://www.amazon.com/oc/echo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Echo</a>&nbsp;we're about need to deal with a lot of these things, and it seems to me it's not so much the technology as the user psychology that we need to pay the most attention to, and so we&nbsp;need to ask what we know about these things already.&nbsp;</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Discussing this with <a href="http://www.alekskrotoski.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dr Krotoski</a>, my very local social psychologist, I was pointed to the seminal paper,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/1412188"><em>The Dynamogenic Factors in Pacemaking and Competition</em></a><em>, by Norman Triplett,&nbsp;</em><a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=amerjpsyc"><em>The American Journal of Psychology&nbsp;</em></a><em>&nbsp;Vol. 9, No. 4 (Jul., 1898)&nbsp;, pp. 507-533.</em></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">This is basically the ur-text of Social Psychology. You can read the original paper for details of the experiment, but the simplified&nbsp;conclusion was this: if a person is being watched, they find easy things easier, and harder things harder. It turns out, from other experiments, that this is true for many species. For example, cockroaches will find their way through mazes much more quickly if they have spectators too, (<a href="http://www.psychwiki.com/wiki/Zajonc,_R._B._(1965)._Social_facilitation._Science,_149,_269-274." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Zajonc, R. B. (1965). Social facilitation. Science, 149, 269-274.</em></a>)</p>&nbsp;








  

    
  
    <div
        class="
          image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
        "
        data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper"
    >

      

      
        <figure
            class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            "
            style="max-width:100%;"
        >
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <div
              
                style="padding-bottom:48.29721450805664%;"
              
              class="
                image-block-wrapper
                
          
        
                has-aspect-ratio
              "
              data-animation-role="image"
              
  

          >
            <noscript><img src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1421662455339-KLZDUK5RBVGVCKFIP7NM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKqRAgLEuFzSNp46T4vH-CZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVG26xzqA9g6lpFYWSuQIG8CNoziv9KJTz0Es_ax8UShuLvH7D-_UHfjyPkGgRqGAeU/image-asset.jpeg" alt="A maze for cockroaches, with spectator seating." /></noscript><img class="thumb-image" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1421662455339-KLZDUK5RBVGVCKFIP7NM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKqRAgLEuFzSNp46T4vH-CZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVG26xzqA9g6lpFYWSuQIG8CNoziv9KJTz0Es_ax8UShuLvH7D-_UHfjyPkGgRqGAeU/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1421662455339-KLZDUK5RBVGVCKFIP7NM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKqRAgLEuFzSNp46T4vH-CZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVG26xzqA9g6lpFYWSuQIG8CNoziv9KJTz0Es_ax8UShuLvH7D-_UHfjyPkGgRqGAeU/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="323x156" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="A maze for cockroaches, with spectator seating." data-load="false" data-image-id="54bcd8f6e4b06b2bad9322ac" data-type="image" />
          </div>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption class="image-caption-wrapper">
            <div class="image-caption"><p class="">A maze for cockroaches, with spectator seating.</p></div>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


&nbsp;<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Further research, specifically&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18074704">Social facilitation effects of virtual humans, Park,&nbsp;Hum Factors.&nbsp;2007 Dec;49(6):1054-60</a>, went on to the nub of it: "Virtual Humans" produce the same social facilitation effect. In other words, the presence of a bot will make simple things simpler, and hard things harder, simply by just being there "watching".</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">This, it seems to me, is quite a big deal. If we're designing systems with even a hint of skeuomorphic similarity to a conscious thing - even if it just has a smiley face and a pretty voice&nbsp;- it might make sense for it to ostentatiously absent itself when it detects the user doing something difficult. This might be the post-singularity reading of the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.footprints-inthe-sand.com/index.php?page=Poem/Poem.php">Footprints In The Sand</a> story, but nerd-rapture aside, it's an interesting question: when is it best for context-aware technology to decide to disappear? When the going is easy, or when the going gets tough?</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Furthermore,&nbsp;I'm not sure if we know yet the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uncanny_valley" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Uncanny Valley</a>-like threshold of "humanness" that triggers the social facilitation effect:&nbsp;do cameras have the same effect? Or even just&nbsp;the knowledge that someone is surveilling you?&nbsp;But this has serious implications beyond AI design.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">For example,&nbsp;the trend for the <a href="http://www.wired.com/2013/05/quantified-self-how-about-a-quantified-workplace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">quantified workplace</a>, where managers can gather statistical data on their employees' activities, might be counterproductive, not simply because of the sheer awfulness of metrics, but because the knowledge they are being watched might make the more complex tasks that employee needs to do inherently more difficult, and hence more unlikely to be attempted in the first place. </p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">For the most challenging tasks we face, the problems&nbsp;requiring the most cognitive effort, and the most imaginative approaches, we may find that many of our current social addictions - surveillance, testing, and so on, might be deeply harmful. "It looks like you're&nbsp;writing a letter," as <a href="http://knowyourmeme.com/memes/clippy">Clippy would say</a>, "would&nbsp;you like me to make that sub-conciously more&nbsp;difficult for you?"&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-01-19 10:32:17]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-01-19 10:32:17]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2015-1-19-socialfacilitationandbots]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="complex-systems"><![CDATA[Complex Systems]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="futures"><![CDATA[Futures]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="wearables"><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Possible Problems of Persona Politeness</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2015/07/17/2015-7-17-possible-problems-of-persona-politeness/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 21:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2015/07/17/2015-7-17-possible-problems-of-persona-politeness/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of my AIs is funnier than the other. This is proving to be a problem.</p><p>But first, consider how the amazing becomes normal very quickly. It feels like I've been using Siri on my phone my entire life, Siri on the iPad charging by my bed since forever, and&nbsp;Siri on my watch since last summer. I've not, of course. She's only four years old this October. But nevertheless, as with any new life-spanning tech, she's become background-banal, in a good way, remarkably quickly. Voice interfaces are, without a doubt, A Thing.</p><p>And so it is with Alexa, the persona of the Amazon Echo, living in my kitchen for the past fortnight. She became a completely integrated part of family life almost immediately. Walking into the kitchen in the morning, ten-month-old daughter in one hand, making my wife tea with the other, I can turn on the lights, listen to the latest news from the radio, check my diary, and order more milk, just by speaking aloud, then turn it all off again as I leave. It's a technological sprezzatura sequence that never fails to make me smile. Thanks, Alexa, I say. Good morning.</p><p>But there's the rub. Alexa doesn't acknowledge my thanks. There's no banter, no trill of mutual appreciation, no silly little, "it is you who must be thanked" line. She just sits there sullenly, silently, ignoring my pleasantries.&nbsp;</p><p>And this is starting to feel weird, and makes me wonder if there's an uncanny valley for politeness. Not one based on listening comprehension, or natural language parsing, but one based on the little rituals of social interaction. If I ask a person, say, what the weather is going to be, and they answer, I thank them, and they reply back to that thanks, and we part happy. If I ask Alexa what the weather is, and thank her, she ignores my thanks. I feel, insanely but even so, snubbed. Or worse, that I've snubbed her.</p><p>It's a little wrinkle in what is really a miraculous device, but it's a serious thing: The Amazon Echo differs from Siri in that it's a communally available service. Interactions with Alexa are available to, and obvious to, everyone in the house, and my inability to be polite with her has a knock-on effect. My daughter is too young to speak yet, but she does see and hear all of our interactions with Alexa. I worry what sort of precedent we are setting for her, in terms of her own future interactions with bots and AIs as well as with people, if she hears me being forced into impolite conversations because of the limitations of her household AI's interface. It's the computing equivilent of being rude to waitresses. We shouldn't allow it, and certainly not by lack of design. Worries about toddler screen time are nothing, compared to future worries about not inadvertently teaching your child to be rude to robots.&nbsp;</p><p>It's not an outlandish thought. I, myself, am&nbsp;already starting to distinguish between the personalities of the different bots in my life. Phone Siri is funnier than Watch Siri;&nbsp;Slackbot is cheeky, and might need reeducating;&nbsp;iPad Siri seems shy and isolated. From these personalities, from these interactions, we'll take our cues. Not only in how to interact, but when and where, and what we can do together. If Watch Siri was funnier, I'd talk to her more. If Phone Siri was more pre-emptive, our relationship might change. And it's in the little, non-critical interactions that their character comes through.</p><p>All this is, of course, easier said than done by someone who isn't a member of the Amazon design team - hey there lab126, beers on me if you're in LA soon - but there's definitely interesting scope to grow for the seemingly extraneous stuff that actually makes all the difference. Personality Design for AIs. That's a fun playground. Is anyone playing there?</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-07-17 21:39:23]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-07-17 21:39:23]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2015-7-17-possible-problems-of-persona-politeness]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="augmentation"><![CDATA[Augmentation]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="futures"><![CDATA[Futures]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="wearables"><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The French Onion Soup Test for Futurism.</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2018/05/15/2018-5-15-the-french-onion-soup-test/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 22:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2018/05/15/2018-5-15-the-french-onion-soup-test/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><em>I appear to have started blogging again. This is for my own self, really, and so I cannot claim it will make sense to anyone else. Still: onwards.&nbsp;</em></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Like a tribe lost to civilization, I've worked for myself for so long I've developed my own language, and it's mostly gibberish to everyone else. Then I lose track of which vocab is which, and end up confusing everyone.&nbsp;For all the poor souls who have heard me talk about The French Onion Soup Test recently, I apologize. Turns out that's only a thing in my head.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">But it might be useful for you, so here we are. The French Onion Soup Test started as a test for cookbooks. Should you find yourself leafing through a cookbook, thinking of buying it, turn to the recipe for French Onion Soup, and see how long it quotes for the caramelizing of the onions. As <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/scocca/2012/05/how_to_cook_onions_why_recipe_writers_lie_and_lie_about_how_long_they_take_to_caramelize_.html">Tom Scocca wrote in Slate back in 2012, seeding this in my mind,&nbsp;</a>&nbsp;most cookbooks are total bullshitters when it comes to this. They'll quote ten minutes, when it's actually more than an hour.&nbsp;</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">One cannot help suspect that the French Onion Soup test means that the recipe either hasn't been tried by the author, or that they feel the need to sell it to the reader in some curious way. Which is weird, because you realize just how wrong the recipe is the first time you cook it. (French Onion Soup done right, by the way, takes all damn day. It is worth it, but...yeah...)</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Anyway this, it turns out, is a really useful test for technology, and especially for thought-stopping jargon-nouns. Substitute "cook the onions for five minutes until they're brown and softened" with "by using the Blockchain" or "utilizing the power of deep learning", or whatever other Futurist product you find yourself examining,&nbsp;and you can possibly see the technique in action. Ask yourself, is this scenario passing the French Onion Soup Test or not? If not, maybe the whole cookbook is wrong.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">For the record, <a href="https://www.epicurious.com/recipes/member/views/thomas-kellers-onion-soup-50070897" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thomas Keller's recipe</a> is tremendous.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">&nbsp;</p><a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/29183526@N06/5140901056/" title="French Onion Soup"><img width="100%"  src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4149/5140901056_15d14c6a44_n.jpg" alt="French Onion Soup"></a><script async src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>5</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-05-15 22:34:53]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-05-15 22:34:53]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2018-5-15-the-french-onion-soup-test]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="futures"><![CDATA[Futures]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Competence Porn</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2019/10/22/2019-10-22-competence-porn/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 16:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2019/10/22/2019-10-22-competence-porn/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><em>Originally Published in British Airways Business Life magazine in September 2019</em></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">I’m moving house right now, and so my thoughts have turned to porn. Now, now. Wait a second. Not the regular kind, or even the location-location-location sort that comes with getting onto the mailing lists of real estate agents in the new city a few thousand miles away from the old. Instead, it’s Competence Porn. Because while I type this, all of our worldly possessions are being wrapped and packed by three very nice Angelenos who are good, but not nearly as good as the Japanese moving company employees I am watching on YouTube to keep myself from interfering with their work.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Competence Porn is the genre of footage found all over YouTube that shows people being low-key awesome at something. Exhibiting skills so profound that they elevate seemingly regular jobs, or even commonplace daily activities, to levels of artistry you’ve never imagined, all while giving an air of being entirely unstressed by the effort. It is profoundly calming. Renaissance-era Italians had a word for this: sprezzatura, and the Japanese moving firms videos are my go-to dose when things are getting too much in real life. Watching them bow before they enter a house, removing their shoes, lining the walls and falls with scuff-protecting panels, then individually wrapping everything in custom-made boxes perfectly shaped for the items at hand, and packing every cupboard into boxes designed so that they can be unpacked into similar cupboards at the destination address with everything in the same exact place, well, it is so profoundly good, so profoundly pleasing, so profoundly moving in its competence that it puts the world back on its axis. Nothing can be truly hopeless when such people exist.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">It’s not just movers that can claim full Competence Porn status. There are videos from a Chicago-based art restoration company, Baumgartner Restoration, that are the CP equivalent of mainlining heroin. There are whole sections of YouTube dedicated to professional car-detailers that will sooth your soul. Sugarcraft, metal tool restoration, even the guys who unblock drains for a living have spawned accounts with millions of subscribers who find deep solace in footage of skilled craftsmen using high-pressure jets to dislodge chunks of badness from pipes. And I am one of them, I must admit. I could give up watching these things any time I want, I would say to myself at 3am, just after this one more.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">As soothing and as world-righting as it is, Competence porn-addiction is not without its potential downsides. Much as some blame media images of unobtainable physical perfection - on the fashion pages, or the covers of men’s protein-shakes’n’pseudo-science magazines - as a contributing factor to many peoples’ low self-esteem, there is the risk that an over consumption of images of profound ability might lead to you never trying to do anything, on the basis that you are currently terrible, or a paralysis of profound disappointment when you encounter the real thing and it’s not as good as the TV version. This is especially so when the CP is the fictional sub-genre. For example, I’ve personally worked with very senior government officials in three countries, and the realization that none of them were anywhere close to the West Wing’s Leo McGarry (the OG of stand-and-salute fictional-CP scenes) was profoundly disillusioning. This isn’t an uncommon example, according to both Westminster and Washington lore.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">But it is the former issue that is perhaps the more serious. Ira Glass, the American radio producer and presenter whose style has influenced a whole generation of broadcasters and, especially, podcasters, calls it the Taste Gap. “All of us who do creative work, we get into it because we have good taste. But there is this gap.” He has said, “For the first couple years you make stuff, it’s just not that good. It’s trying to be good, it has potential, but it’s not. But your taste, the thing that got you into the game, is still killer. And your taste is why your work disappoints you. A lot of people never get past this phase, they quit.”</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">We are left with a real choice here. On the one hand, we can see profound mastery as an unobtainable state. One to be admired, or one to dash our hopes against, but either way a thing that is not for us. Or we can better see it as rather just the current situation of someone who is simply further along on the same journey as we are. Today’s generation of innovation experts and personal efficacy coaches have a name for this: the Growth Mindset. This is the way of thinking that says that with the correct application of proper effort, you can absolutely become the person as skilled as want to be, and that your current slightly-rubbish state is a necessary part of that path. Personal growth, and innovation at every level from the private to the corporate to the national depends on this mindset, and for the sake of the rest of the century, we should practice it. As I am, right now, getting to the good bit: the special box for televisions. It’s like a dream.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>7</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-22 16:32:14]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-22 16:32:14]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2019-10-22-competence-porn]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="writing"><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>When reality looks like sci-fi world building</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/04/30/when-reality-looks-like-sci-fi-world-building/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 20:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2020/04/30/when-reality-looks-like-sci-fi-world-building/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"id":179,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/13bc8c20-26ff-4d8e-993a-a29442016d3d-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-179"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>180</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-04-30 16:43:36]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-04-30 20:43:36]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[when-reality-looks-like-sci-fi-world-building]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="images-from-the-future"><![CDATA[Images From The Future]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[179]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Liked Links - May 1</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/05/01/liked-links/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 22:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/?p=182</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Process Philosophy</strong>: Process philosophy is based on the premise that being is dynamic and that the dynamic nature of being should be the primary focus of any comprehensive philosophical account of reality and our place within it. - by permeating - <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/process-philosophy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/process-philosophy/</a></p>
<p><strong>Seattle’s Leaders Let Scientists Take the Lead. New York’s Did Not</strong>: The first diagnosis of the coronavirus in the United States occurred in mid-January, in a Seattle suburb not far from the hospital where Dr. Francis Riedo, an infectious-disease specialist, works. - by Charles Duhigg - <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/05/04/seattles-leaders-let-scientists-take-the-lead-new-yorks-did-not" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/05/04/seattles-leaders-let-scientists-take-the-lead-new-yorks-did-not</a></p>
<p><strong>Hail the maintainers</strong>: Innovation is a dominant ideology of our era, embraced in America by Silicon Valley, Wall Street, and the Washington DC political elite. - by Lee Vinsel, Andrew Russell - <a href="https://aeon.co/essays/innovation-is-overvalued-maintenance-often-matters-more" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://aeon.co/essays/innovation-is-overvalued-maintenance-often-matters-more</a></p>
<p><strong>After dread</strong>: Where everyone seems to agree is that things can’t go back the way they were. As Fred Scharmen says, this isn’t the end of the world, but it’s certainly the end of a world. - by Cennydd Bowles - <a href="https://www.cennydd.com/blog/after-dread" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.cennydd.com/blog/after-dread</a></p>
<p><strong>Plot Economics</strong>: For the fourth time in my adult memory, humanity has collectively, visibly lost the plot at a global level. My criteria are fairly restrictive: The dotcom bust and the 2007 crash don’t make my list for instance, and neither do previous recent epidemics like SARS or Ebola. - by Venkatesh Rao - <a href="https://www.ribbonfarm.com/2020/03/09/plot-economics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.ribbonfarm.com/2020/03/09/plot-economics/</a></p>
<p><strong>Feral Cities, Pandemics, and the Military</strong>: In this episode of MWI’s Urban Warfare Project podcast, John Spencer is joined by Dr. Richard Norton. He is a professor of national security affairs at the US Naval War College and a retired US Navy commander. - by John Spencer - <a href="https://mwi.usma.edu/feral-cities-pandemics-military/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://mwi.usma.edu/feral-cities-pandemics-military/</a></p>
<p><strong>Exclusive: Mary Meeker's coronavirus trends report</strong>: Bond Capital, a Silicon Valley VC firm whose portfolio companies include Slack and Uber, told its investors this morning via email that the coronavirus' high-speed spread and impact has similarities to the devastating San Francisco earthquake of 1906. - by Michael Kovac - <a href="https://www.axios.com/mary-meeker-coronavirus-trends-report-0690fc96-294f-47e6-9c57-573f829a6d7c.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.axios.com/mary-meeker-coronavirus-trends-report-0690fc96-294f-47e6-9c57-573f829a6d7c.html</a></p>
<p><strong>We Were Wrong: So Sorry that We Ruined Your Life</strong>: Andrew Cuomo, governor of New York, is moving up in the betting odds for getting the Democratic presidential nomination, even though he is not running. The reason is that binge-watching newshounds have noticed something about his comportment during this crisis. - by Jeffrey Tucker - <a href="https://www.aier.org/article/we-were-wrong-so-sorry-that-we-ruined-your-life/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.aier.org/article/we-were-wrong-so-sorry-that-we-ruined-your-life/</a></p>
<p><strong>China starts testing digital currency as Facebook's Libra faces setback</strong>: Trial programs for China’s sovereign digital currency began last week as Libra, a cryptocurrency backed by Facebook, scaled back its ambitions to become a global currency. - <a href="https://www.abacusnews.com/tech/china-starts-testing-digital-currency-facebooks-libra-faces-setback/article/3080713" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.abacusnews.com/tech/china-starts-testing-digital-currency-facebooks-libra-faces-setback/article/3080713</a></p>
<p><strong>If you landed in a foreign country with no documentation, could you prove who you are?</strong>: How would you do it? There are three traditional pillars of identity. The first is documents. The second is biometric — your appearance, your fingerprints, etc. This can only be used if a record of your biometrics is on file somewhere, which (thankfully) is uncommon. - by McKinley Valentine - <a href="https://medium.com/paper-giant/if-you-landed-in-a-foreign-country-with-no-documentation-could-you-prove-who-you-are-8290282608a0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://medium.com/paper-giant/if-you-landed-in-a-foreign-country-with-no-documentation-could-you-prove-who-you-are-8290282608a0</a></p>

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>182</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-05-01 18:27:21]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-01 22:27:21]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[close]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[liked-links]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="links"><![CDATA[Links]]></category>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-link"><![CDATA[Link]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_abt_state]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{"references":[],"style":{"kind":"predefined","value":"apa-old-doi-prefix","label":"American Psychological Association 6th edition (\"doi:\" DOI prefix)","shortTitle":"APA"}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_b2s_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:8:"og_title";s:19:"Liked Links - May 1";s:7:"og_desc";s:160:"Process Philosophy: Process philosophy is based on the premise that being is dynamic and that the dynamic nature of being should be the primary focus of any com";s:8:"og_image";s:0:"";s:10:"card_title";s:19:"Liked Links - May 1";s:9:"card_desc";s:160:"Process Philosophy: Process philosophy is based on the premise that being is dynamic and that the dynamic nature of being should be the primary focus of any com";s:10:"card_image";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Liked Links - April 30</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/04/30/liked-links-april-30/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 02:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/?p=191</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>The Signal Code: A Rights Based Approach to Information During Crisis</strong>: 1. The Right to Information 2. The Right to Protection from Harm 3. The Right to Data Security and Privacy 4. The Right to Data Agency 5. The Right to Redress and Rectification - by Authors - <a href="https://signalcode.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://signalcode.org/</a>

<strong>Don’t just talk - show your work!</strong>: To take one specific example - coding - Github-type tools are uber-collaborative, but the typical user is perhaps wearing headphones and very much in a do-not-disturb work mode. - <a href="https://postshift.activehosted.com/social/01161aaa0b6d1345dd8fe4e481144d84.231" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://postshift.activehosted.com/social/01161aaa0b6d1345dd8fe4e481144d84.231</a>

<strong>To Run My Best Marathon at Age 44, I Had to Outrun My Past</strong>: Running is the simplest of sports: right foot, left foot, right foot. But the simplicity opens up complexity. There's no ball to focus on, no mat to land on, no one charging toward you with their shoulder down. And so your attention shifts inward. - by Nicholas Thompson - <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/marathon-speed-tech-training-outrunning-my-past/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.wired.com/story/marathon-speed-tech-training-outrunning-my-past/</a>

<strong>#15: Maintenance by design</strong>: I’m an author, organizational sociologist, strategy professor, unsuccessful furniture maker, and Xoogler—this is yet another of my attempts to make sense of the state of not-knowing. The ideas below are only partially baked. - by Vaughn Tan - <a href="https://uncertaintymindset.substack.com/p/15-maintenance-by-design" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://uncertaintymindset.substack.com/p/15-maintenance-by-design</a>

<strong>Two Kinds Of Caution</strong>: Financial Times: What We Get Wrong About Technology. It cites boring advances like barbed wire and shipping containers to argue that some of the most transformative inventions are not the product of complicated high technology but just some clever hacks that manage to revolutionize everyday living. - by Scott Alexander - <a href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2017/07/08/two-kinds-of-caution/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://slatestarcodex.com/2017/07/08/two-kinds-of-caution/</a>

<strong>Strategic Warning: If Surprise is Inevitable, What Role for Analysis?</strong>: 1. Clarify the Warning Mission Any critical examination of the mission of warning analysis should give primacy of place to avoidance or limitation of damage—and not to the unrealistic standard of avoidance of surprise. - <a href="https://www.cia.gov/library/kent-center-occasional-papers/vol2no1.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.cia.gov/library/kent-center-occasional-papers/vol2no1.htm</a>

<strong>The Cofounders</strong>: Meta-systematicity manifests as the forefront of all domains of meaning, including in personal psychology, rational understanding, social organization, and culture. - by Meaningness - <a href="https://meaningness.com/cofounders-in-relationship" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://meaningness.com/cofounders-in-relationship</a>

<strong>We’re not going back to normal</strong>: It’s now widely agreed (even by Britain, finally) that every country needs to “flatten the curve”: impose social distancing to slow the spread of the virus so that the number of people sick at once doesn’t cause the health-care system to collapse, as it is threatening to do in Italy right no - by GIDEON LICHFIELD - <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/03/17/905264/coronavirus-pandemic-social-distancing-18-months/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/03/17/905264/coronavirus-pandemic-social-distancing-18-months/</a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>191</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-04-30 22:27:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-01 02:27:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[close]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[liked-links-april-30]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="links"><![CDATA[Links]]></category>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-link"><![CDATA[Link]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_abt_state]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{"references":[],"style":{"kind":"predefined","value":"apa-old-doi-prefix","label":"American Psychological Association 6th edition (\"doi:\" DOI prefix)","shortTitle":"APA"}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_b2s_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:8:"og_title";s:22:"Liked Links - April 30";s:7:"og_desc";s:160:"The Signal Code: A Rights Based Approach to Information During Crisis: 1. The Right to Information 2. The Right to Protection from Harm 3. The Right to Data Sec";s:8:"og_image";s:0:"";s:10:"card_title";s:22:"Liked Links - April 30";s:9:"card_desc";s:160:"The Signal Code: A Rights Based Approach to Information During Crisis: 1. The Right to Information 2. The Right to Protection from Harm 3. The Right to Data Sec";s:10:"card_image";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2020-05-01]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The Internet of Tells: Constant biomonitoring and some uses</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2014/12/30/2014-12-28-the-internet-of-tells/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 10:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2014/12/30/2014-12-28-the-internet-of-tells/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In poker, they call them <a target="_blank" href="#" rel="noopener noreferrer">tells</a>. The little physical signs that we can't control that give away our inner mental state. What happens if we make these privately machine-readable?</p><p>For me, a lot of the fun of future technologies isn't new&nbsp;tech per se, but the coming together of three or four older things, refined&nbsp;by new physical capabilities and design understandings, to push over the Hill of Single Use&nbsp;into a new valley of possible products. A strained metaphor, perhaps, so let me give you an example. Heart rate monitors have been around for years. I've been running with one strapped to my chest for at least a decade myself, and in those days the data has been restricted to its one single device (and later to a single app, barring the export of averages and such very high-level takes). You certainly didn't wear an HR monitor all the time, and even if you did, you couldn't use what it saw for anything other than athletic training.</p><p>But 2015 will see at least two products come to mass-market that might do such a thing. The <a target="_blank" href="http://jawbone.com/store/buy/up3" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jawbone3</a>, and the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.apple.com/watch/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apple Watch</a>.&nbsp;</p>







 

  
  
    <div
        class="
          image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-overlay-hover
          design-layout-inline
          
          
          
        "
        data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper"
    >

      

      
        <figure
            class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            "
            style="max-width:280.0px;"
        >
          
        
        

        
          
            <button
                class="
                  sqs-block-image-button
                  lightbox
                  
          
        
                "
                data-description="&lt;p&gt;The back of the Apple Watch, showing the HR monitor&lt;/p&gt;"
                data-lightbox-theme=""
            >
              <span class="v6-visually-hidden">View fullsize</span>
              
          <div
              
                style="padding-bottom:64.28571319580078%;"
              
              class="
                image-block-wrapper
                
          
        
                
              "
              data-animation-role="image"
              
  data-animation-override

          >
            <noscript><img src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1419932374733-X0Y31PL4PSHDS88LYZH2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCZ1hl-knJwHoNrB8RiFpFJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWhcwhEtWJXoshNdA9f1qD7Xj1nVWs2aaTtWBneO2WM-tADwIAB3Wp0q21M55hJnJCZCj2614B64-uQAk64TZiHQ/applewatch+heartrate+monitor.jpeg" alt="The back of the Apple Watch, showing the HR monitor" /></noscript><img class="thumb-image" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1419932374733-X0Y31PL4PSHDS88LYZH2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCZ1hl-knJwHoNrB8RiFpFJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWhcwhEtWJXoshNdA9f1qD7Xj1nVWs2aaTtWBneO2WM-tADwIAB3Wp0q21M55hJnJCZCj2614B64-uQAk64TZiHQ/applewatch+heartrate+monitor.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1419932374733-X0Y31PL4PSHDS88LYZH2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCZ1hl-knJwHoNrB8RiFpFJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWhcwhEtWJXoshNdA9f1qD7Xj1nVWs2aaTtWBneO2WM-tADwIAB3Wp0q21M55hJnJCZCj2614B64-uQAk64TZiHQ/applewatch+heartrate+monitor.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="280x180" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="The back of the Apple Watch, showing the HR monitor" data-load="false" data-image-id="54a272d6e4b045b450277930" data-type="image" />
          </div>
        
            </button>
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption class="image-caption-wrapper">
            <div class="image-caption"><p>The back of the Apple Watch, showing the HR monitor</p></div>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  



<p>The Apple Watch has an HR monitor on its back, has local processing, a data connection (and through that, infinite cloud processing) - but more than that, it has access to everything else we might do digitally, Not just publishing capability (send my HR to Facebook, Tweet when I go over 180, and so on) but a form of sense-making too. The complex network around the Apple Watch knows an awful lot about your personal context - that's really its&nbsp;point after all - and so it could start to make all sorts of correlations between HR and that context.</p><p>We know that changes in HR can reflect changes in psychological state. Your heart beats faster when you're aroused or stressed or angry. And we now have a device that can notice that tell, and try to work out what is causing it. What might that do? Here are some scenarios, and possible products:</p><ol><li><strong>One to One.</strong> You regularly meet with someone, Mr X,&nbsp;who drives you insane. A deeply stressful person, who causes your heart to beat hard as you restrain yourself from violence. An asshole of the highest order. Your system detects the increase in heart rate, and sees it happens whenever you have a calendar&nbsp;appointment with Mr X. Matching the appointment data with LinkedIN, it identifies Mr X, and posts the "Meeting with Mr X is stressful" posit to a LinkedIN API-using offshoot, a "Rate My Meeting" clone. Over time, Mr X's rating is further added to by others' systems, perhaps without user input at all, flagging Mr X as (algorithmically designated) asshole. The system acts accordingly.</li><li><strong>Many to One. </strong>You walk to work down Oxford Street, but prefer to slip through side streets if the foot traffic is annoyingly dense. Luckily, the HR monitors on the wrists of tens of Apple Watch wearers already on Oxford Street are spiking higher than they usually average here, at this time of day, with this sort of weather. Your system notices this, and gently nudges you away from the area, pre-emptively avoiding the stress that others are giving away to the network.</li><li><strong>Many to Many</strong>. You're at a concert, and having a splendid time. Your HR is rising as the music builds, and from your watch you can see that others in the crowd are feeling it too. The crowd average HR goes past 140...141...144....147.......149......and as soon as it&nbsp;reaches 150, &nbsp;it triggers the drop, the stage pyros, the lasers, the dancing girls. The musicians onstage, able to reach their musical climax just as the audience reaches theirs. That's showbusiness.</li></ol><p>None of these use-cases, and there are many more, require a new magical technology. Apart from the actual heart-monitoring, you could prototype them today all quite (handwaving here)&nbsp;easily. But none of them would work without a good installed base of constantly available HR monitors already in place. That, if Apple and Jawbone and the rest get their way, is what we're about to have. It's a whole new product/service category, being unlocked almost by mistake.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>220</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-12-30 10:22:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-30 10:22:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2014-12-28-the-internet-of-tells]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="augmentation"><![CDATA[Augmentation]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="futures"><![CDATA[Futures]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="wearables"><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Future-Dense Sentences</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2014/12/31/2014-12-31-future-dense-sentences/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2014/12/31/2014-12-31-future-dense-sentences/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">There's a technique for pondering emerging technologies&nbsp;that originated, I think, with Jamais Cascio. Imagine you'd been instantly transported back in time x years in a particular place.&nbsp;How many years would you have to have travelled&nbsp;before you noticed you had slipped back in time? What would give it away?&nbsp;People's clothing? The music on the radio? Headlines on newspapers in the first papershop you come across? The cars, the phones people are carrying, the TVs you can see through the windows you pass? Sat where you are now, could you tell if you'd suddenly dropped back to 2006? 2001? 1989?</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Ok, you're on the internet, so that breaks that, but it's a fun game to play if you travel a lot, and can be also quite revealing within institutional buildings. Applied to business processes or cultural values, it can uncover&nbsp;a good deal too.&nbsp;</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">My variation on this is to look for the places, or the ideas, or the writing, that is the most future-dense. What sentences can we find that contains the most stuff that, were we to fall back in time only a few years, would make no sense whatsoever. What contains the most embedded understanding of wholly modern concepts. Here's a good one, from this morning:</p>


 
   <blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>There are bots that scan GitHub for accidentally shared AWS keys and use them to run EC2 instances to mine bitcoins <a href="http://t.co/rQDOeIhE0D">http://t.co/rQDOeIhE0D</a></p>— Simon Willison (@simonw) <a href="https://twitter.com/simonw/status/550104391001182208">December 31, 2014</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
 

<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">See what I mean? Go back ten years, and that would be crazy. Go back thirty years, and you'd have to start from such first principles, you'd be considered mad.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Here's another from earlier this year, that at first glance reads, technologically at least,&nbsp;entirely, boringly, banal:</p>








  

    
  
    <div
        class="
          image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-hidden
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
        "
        data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper"
    >

      

      
        <figure
            class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            "
            style="max-width:100%;"
        >
          
        
        

        
          
            <button
                class="
                  sqs-block-image-button
                  lightbox
                  
          
        
                "
                data-description=""
                data-lightbox-theme="dark"
            >
              <span class="v6-visually-hidden">View fullsize</span>
              
          <div
              
                style="padding-bottom:66.66667175292969%;"
              
              class="
                image-block-wrapper
                
          
        
                has-aspect-ratio
              "
              data-animation-role="image"
              
  

          >
            <noscript><img src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1420020572985-G0SQ0MYM4KT1R17CP9OI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKu9P3xdYr2DDKikXxfN0o1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyZSzqXkO-ceUw9OkBkjNh15ehP2McgVZ5PPyznDt9ZSyyW3MUxZombM6QN6iolFFI/image-asset.jpeg" alt="" /></noscript><img class="thumb-image" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1420020572985-G0SQ0MYM4KT1R17CP9OI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKu9P3xdYr2DDKikXxfN0o1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyZSzqXkO-ceUw9OkBkjNh15ehP2McgVZ5PPyznDt9ZSyyW3MUxZombM6QN6iolFFI/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1420020572985-G0SQ0MYM4KT1R17CP9OI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKu9P3xdYr2DDKikXxfN0o1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyZSzqXkO-ceUw9OkBkjNh15ehP2McgVZ5PPyznDt9ZSyyW3MUxZombM6QN6iolFFI/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="660x440" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="54a3cb5ce4b010b9ae1f7a67" data-type="image" />
          </div>
        
            </button>
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">If you fell back thirty years to 1985, think of all the things about this screenshot you'd have to explain, and all the layers you'd have to fill in before you could. "Ok, so...[deep breath] the President of the United States is a black man named Barack Obama. Yes, really.&nbsp;This is a message he has left on a microblogging service on the web...ermmm, it's a service based around a new hypertext protocol on the internet. Yes, that thing the scientists use. Kinda like a bbs, yes. But with a few billion users. Yes. Billion. With a B.&nbsp;Anyway, he's saying he's going to binge-watch a show on Netflix. Netflix? It's a streaming video site...oh...well, it's a place...errrrr...Retweets? Spoilers?...I...you know...I think we should drop it."</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Anyway, looking for these brings me to a couple of things. Firstly, it's a useful koan-like personal thought experiment to find new insights around a place or an organisation or a cultural moment. At the very least, it's entertaining.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">But secondly, I think it raises, once again, the realisation that our future world is heavily, fundamentally layered: that problems have no simple solution that a single technology plonked on top will fix. Instead, it is the interplay of the complex systems - complex, not necessarily complicated - of culture, technology, politics, culture and so on&nbsp;that will come together to make tomorrow's banal commonplace thing. That complexity, I think, is both deeply exciting, and - hopefully - humbling. The future is&nbsp;not about the tech. It's perhaps the other way around.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>221</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-12-31 10:36:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-31 10:36:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2014-12-31-future-dense-sentences]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="complex-systems"><![CDATA[Complex Systems]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="futures"><![CDATA[Futures]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Right Effort, Right Interface</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2018/05/15/2018-5-15-a-watching-brief/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 21:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2018/05/15/2018-5-15-a-watching-brief/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So here's irony.&nbsp;If I stare straight ahead right now, all I can see are screens. My new desk, with my new monitor setup, takes up almost all of my field of view, and yet, as luxurious as this is, it's lead me to hours at a time away from screens altogether.</p><p>Here's the thing: while for some types of work, two (or, swoon, three) big monitors and some associated ergonomically enhancing desk set up would seem to be the thing, (see <a target="_blank" href="http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1541931213601572" rel="noopener noreferrer">Multiple Screens and Devices in an Information-rich Environment</a>, for example), I'm profoundly loathe to sit at a desk all day. I live in Southern California, and there's sunshine I don't want to miss out on.</p><p>Moreover the years of following a <a target="_blank" href="https://gettingthingsdone.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">GTD practice</a>&nbsp;have lead me to realize the power of breaking my work up into chunks of, so to say,&nbsp;right-thing, right-place, right time. Being able to escape one form of computing, and with it, the form of thinking that is implied and enforced by those tools, is a powerful technique.</p><p>At the same time, as a student of Zen Buddhism, I'm trying to pay attention, in a very active sense, to what I do as a daily practice in all parts of my life. Right now, it's the Spring Practice Period at the <a href="http://sfzc.org">San Francisco Zen Center</a>, (I'm attending online from down here in LA), and the theme this season is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noble_Eightfold_Path#Right_effort">Wise Effort</a>. The associated meditations have me thinking on this anew, and from there, in part, on how much time I spend on my phone.</p><p>Every morning, for example, I take my daughter to school, and we stop off for coffee/steamed milk on the way. Too often have I caught myself engaging with Twitter rather than with her during those brief minutes, and that doesn't require exquisite Zen training to uncover as not-ideal for either of us.</p><p>So for the past few weeks, I've been wrapping my phone up in a cloth, <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Furoshiki" rel="noopener noreferrer">furoshiki</a>-style,&nbsp;and putting it into my bag. The added friction of getting it out, unwrapping it, turning it back on, et-connecting-cetera, takes away the quick hit of checking notifications, and the inevitable in-suck from there. It works well.</p><p>So far, so digital-detox middle-aged-angst. But it has lead to something new.</p>








  

    
  
    <div
        class="
          image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          
          
          
        "
        data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper"
    >

      

      
        <figure
            class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            "
            style="max-width:2379.0px;"
        >
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <div
              
                style="padding-bottom:79.99159240722656%;"
              
              class="
                image-block-wrapper
                
          
        
                has-aspect-ratio
              "
              data-animation-role="image"
              
  data-animation-override

          >
            <noscript><img src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1526414631520-0QI6Z3ZADYY8LNCH9TC1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJnpPWSQgCRWregA1oMwbCd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UR4g-wQ03ZN-y4cdkUUOdpjjBMEPN4swbknwRRBOZZZAPA_rk_ep5dy7fKh_ZuG1aw/IMG_0221.jpg" alt="I need to work on my 風呂敷 technique." /></noscript><img class="thumb-image" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1526414631520-0QI6Z3ZADYY8LNCH9TC1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJnpPWSQgCRWregA1oMwbCd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UR4g-wQ03ZN-y4cdkUUOdpjjBMEPN4swbknwRRBOZZZAPA_rk_ep5dy7fKh_ZuG1aw/IMG_0221.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1526414631520-0QI6Z3ZADYY8LNCH9TC1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJnpPWSQgCRWregA1oMwbCd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UR4g-wQ03ZN-y4cdkUUOdpjjBMEPN4swbknwRRBOZZZAPA_rk_ep5dy7fKh_ZuG1aw/IMG_0221.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2379x1903" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="I need to work on my 風呂敷 technique." data-load="false" data-image-id="5afb3d2503ce64616e969997" data-type="image" />
          </div>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption class="image-caption-wrapper">
            <div class="image-caption"><p>I need to work on my 風呂敷 technique.</p></div>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


<p>Leaving my phone wrapped up is anxiety-driving, because while I know my own work schedule well enough, there's always an ego-driven part of the brain that thinks I'm an air-traffic controller with a part-time heart surgery practice. Those neurons want me to check my inbox on a regular basis, just to make sure I'm not being called into action for something that has to happen right now now now. By, you know, something on Twitter. &nbsp;¯\_(ツ)_/¯</p><p>This is bollocks, obviously, but it's nonetheless an itch that needs to be scratched. Combine it with my podcast-listening habit, and you have two major drives pulling on me to unwrap the thing, so to pull it out every few minutes.</p><p>But I don't. I've defaulted to my watch as my primary mobile platform.&nbsp;Podcasts I can get, after installing <a target="_blank" href="https://crunchybagel.com/outcast-for-apple-watch/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Outcast for Apple Watch</a>, and the rest of my super urgent messages and pushes can be relied on to come through just fine. (Which is to say, never, as I'm not a coastguard).</p><p>Thus becalmed, my brain can get on with other stuff. And here's the new thing. As I mentioned on Twitter yesterday as part of a thread started by the splendid <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/hondanhon" rel="noopener noreferrer">@hondanhon</a>&nbsp;by defaulting to a new, tiny, platform, I'm forced to use its features more deeply. Turns out, they're really good:&nbsp;</p>


 
   <blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I’m going to write it up: it allows my mind to chill about fomo of important messages while I do thinky stuff on paper. I can use Siri to send messages, add stuff to Omnifocus and Cal. 3rd ed watch with a cell connection, and I’ve found a way to get podcasts onto it too.</p>— Ben Hammersley (@benhammersley) <a href="https://twitter.com/benhammersley/status/996084820462600193?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 14, 2018</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
 

<p>Many of my work tasks, it seems, are much better suited by combining the pens and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Maruman-Mnemosyne-Special-Memo-Notepad/dp/B001A1TO14/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1526417888&amp;sr=8-4&amp;keywords=mnemosyne+notebooks">paper of my choice</a> with Siri-based interaction with my watch via AirPods.&nbsp;While my desktop machine has a whole monitor dedicated to my inboxes, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus" rel="noopener noreferrer">Omnifocus</a>, and calendar, and my weekly review is for sure a multiscreen activity, if I'm planning a talk, for example, I just need to send quick messages and drop reminders to myself. I can do that, and even some pretty nice long-form dictation into Evernote, from Siri. I'm both connected to my IT-ecosystem, and pleasingly untethered from it.</p><p>Is it the perfect platform for the entire day? No. But it does speak to an interesting trend. As my phone gets ever more powerful, there's sometimes a feeling that it's <em>too</em> powerful to be brought out without proper psychological preparation. It's too moreish a device to just have in my pocket, and most of the time I have no operational need for it to be quick-draw holstered there either.</p><p>And also, voice interfaces are pretty good - the household menagerie of smart speakers speak to that already - and offer a new way of interacting that doesn't require eyes or fingers. In the kitchen, or the bedroom, a quiet work to an Alexa is almost always cognitively appropriate to the computational task at hand.</p><p>That's what I suppose I'm searching for here: matching an appropriateness of interface to the task, rather than matching my tasks to the interface I have in front of me: deciding what to do based on priorities other than what technology I am sat with.&nbsp;This could involve breaking habits I didn't know I had. Or, at least, having to become aware of how much my available toolset shapes my thinking.&nbsp;Let's see.&nbsp;Onwards.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>222</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-05-15 21:33:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-05-15 21:33:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2018-5-15-a-watching-brief]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="augmentation"><![CDATA[Augmentation]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="complex-systems"><![CDATA[Complex Systems]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="wearables"><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Microgestures</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2019/09/22/2019-10-22-microgestures/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2019/09/22/2019-10-22-microgestures/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><em>Originally Published in British Airways Business Life magazine in September 2019 </em></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">The tiniest movements make all the difference. At least that was what I heard when my wife threatened to burn my glasses if I wore them near her again. These aren’t ordinary glasses, of course. They’re the new Focals by North, which with a combination of a special material embedded inside the lens, a very finely tuned laser projector in the frame, and some delicate fitting, look just like regular glasses but give me a heads-up display of pertinent information. I press the little switch on a ring on my right pointer finger, and a display hovers in the middle of my field of view. The time, or the weather forecast, or how close the Uber I just called is, or the walking directions to my next meeting. They are, in private, on my own, really cool. But if I wear them in the house it all goes downhill very quickly. Because although the display only pops up a few words at a time, and right in the middle of my field of view, my eyes subtly shift. It’s only a matter of a millimeter for a few milliseconds, if that, but it’s enough for someone to notice.&nbsp;</p><p class="" data-rte-preserve-empty="true" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">It isn’t the gross rudeness of ostentatiously taking my phone out from my pocket in the middle of dinner, or pushing back a cuff to look at my watch during a meeting, and certainly not the combination movement of looking at my watch, then swiping around on its face while apologetically looking back at my conversant as if nothing is happening. It’s just a brief flicker, a saccade, a tiny taking in of the new knowledge and then a return to the present moment. But somehow it enrages far more. In trying to hide, or at least deemphasize the physical impact of, these little informational exchanges on the people around me, these new, more personal interfaces seem to actually make things worse. And certainly angrier.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">This isn’t because the alerts I’m getting are trivial. It’s not Twitter, or some faux-important news blast of celeb gossip. Those little pop-ups of information are genuinely life-improving. Knowing that it’s about to start to rain (apps like Dark Skies are almost minute-perfect in this), or that the traffic is getting worse between here and my next appointment, or being able to see texts from a very small list of people I’ve configured it to allow through immediately are all features that have made small but meaningful improvements to my life today alone.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">No, the issue seems to be much more immediate than that. It’s not the nature of the information that seems to upset people, nor really the fact that they can’t see it - they can’t see my more regular screens either - but the idea that I have a secret backchannel to the universe.&nbsp;</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Augmenting my consciousness with a display that, through a network of connections each entirely simple, reaches out to the tiny spaceships that are watching the clouds nearby, and then allows me to know privately that it’s going to start to rain in 90 seconds is as close to magic as you can get. Someone who had that knowledge a decade ago would have been a savant. A century, a fee-charging curiosity. A millennium ago, burnt as a witch. It’s not surprising that others find it indescribably unnerving.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">There seems to be something curious that happens when we take our information closer and closer to our personal experience of the world. New interfaces, like head-up displays, or vibration alerts from watches, or private languages of subtle beeps and tunes from omnipresent airpods, exist to do this: to give us information in a way that bypasses the need to read something from a screen, and instead insert new information directly into our consciousness in the same way as the smell from the kitchen, or the tune from an ice-cream truck does. Without a conscious interpretive step. It’s weirdly unnerving for other people, and we don’t yet have a language to either describe it, or a way to develop an etiquette around it.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">But as our devices and our environment become more connected, the possibility to have, say, a special alert pattern of vibrations from your watch triggered by your partner arriving home, and for that alert pattern to be so familiar a thing that we don’t so much notice it happening as just know they are there, is deeply interesting. My glasses still trigger a tiny moment of taking-in and processing, but soon that process could become more and more second nature.&nbsp;</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">In one way of putting it, a connoisseur is someone who has trained their consciousness to a experience a greater knowledge of the nature of something - wine, coffee, art, whatever - in a way that they cannot explain, but can access. Perhaps the next stage of computing is to make us all like this. Aware of the world around us in whole new ways, but through interfaces we can’t really describe. It won’t be a world of screens. I can just feel it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>223</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-09-22 16:31:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-09-22 16:31:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2019-10-22-microgestures]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="writing"><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Weeknotes, October 22</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2019/10/22/2019-10-22-weeknotes-october-22/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 17:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/2019/10/22/2019-10-22-weeknotes-october-22/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><strong>Hi</strong></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Everything finds its right time. And despite the fact I’ve been writing online for more than 20 years, and have been running my own business for nearly nine, I’ve never been able to settle into the habit of writing about what I’m working on as I’m doing it. While I’ve known for years that&nbsp;<a href="https://medium.com/job-garden/a-pre-history-of-weeknotes-plus-why-i-write-them-and-perhaps-why-you-should-too-week-16-31a4a5cbf7b0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Weeknotes, for example, are profoundly useful</a>&nbsp;for both the reader and the writer, hooo boy have I found myself stuck in the paralyzing gap between neuroses, trigger-shyness, and pressing deadlines.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">But now it feels right to start. If the gap between posts gets too large, feel free to give me a nudge. Hey, say hi anyway. Hi! I’m&nbsp;<a href="mailto:ben@benhammersley.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ben@benhammersley.com</a></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><strong>Slowing it Down with Pencils and Cameras.</strong></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">According to the specialists, I have pretty enthusiastic ADHD.</p><blockquote><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">“We place people with these disorders on a spectrum, Ben. Neurotypical people are here. People with difficulties in school here. People who are usually in prison are here. And you? You’re waaaay over here. Sooooo…Whatever you’re using to compensate, you should keep doing that. But also: drugs!”</p></blockquote><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">It’s of a type that’s been, frankly, kinda useful for my life — though which caused what is an interesting debate — as it’s a subtype that invokes hyper-noticing and connection-making. For a journalist who became a futurist and strategic consultant, the ability to see things and make connections between them that other people have yet to is, well, very useful. People do (you can too!) employee me for this skill. But also as a journalist, and someone who has bashed his head against a desk in the writing of five books and millions of printed words, I have always struggled with the point of the process where I have to get the insight out of my own head and into my client’s. Since my proper diagnosis, I’ve been purposefully working with some practices that genuinely help. Alongside meditation, the one that seems to really help is a return to paper. Introduced to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0996006036" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Christina Wodtke’s Pencil Me In</a>&nbsp;by Dan Hon in his&nbsp;<a href="https://tinyletter.com/danhon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">excellent newsletter</a>&nbsp;I’ve been taking the time to work first on paper, with sketching, away from screens. It slows me down considerably, not least in the act of concentrating on making my letters legible — drawing them, not writing them — but that seems to work wonders for my attention.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">When I added in the habit of printing out all my daily news briefing emails — shrunk down to 4 pages to a sheet — reading those over breakfast with no devices, and pushing the wake-up-to-screen-on time back even just another 30 minutes, my brain, and the rest of the day, is a much happier place.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">That’s all very well for work in isolation, but a lot of my work is collaboration. Not a problem. At a morning at the theatre with my daughter to see the puppeteer&nbsp;<a href="http://lamama.org/tomte/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tom Lee’s “Tomte”</a>&nbsp;I saw him use the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ipevo.com/v4k" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ipevo v4K</a>&nbsp;Here it is on my desk:</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p>








  

    
  
    <div
        class="
          image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
        "
        data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper"
    >

      

      
        <figure
            class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            "
            style="max-width:2186.0px;"
        >
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <div
              
                style="padding-bottom:117.70356750488281%;"
              
              class="
                image-block-wrapper
                
          
        
                has-aspect-ratio
              "
              data-animation-role="image"
              
  

          >
            <noscript><img src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1571766507841-V1B50OL23IYI8TI55EXO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCJXkbCY1jfz-S28OxEpex97gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UWsJH8Yw6GRI4XGuw0v0R875ZDN2AcCq2uvJM1Hx0IPwmjG7iZYqKSDNZuM6IW5uVA/IMG_2343+2.jpeg" alt="IMG_2343 2.jpeg" /></noscript><img class="thumb-image" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1571766507841-V1B50OL23IYI8TI55EXO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCJXkbCY1jfz-S28OxEpex97gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UWsJH8Yw6GRI4XGuw0v0R875ZDN2AcCq2uvJM1Hx0IPwmjG7iZYqKSDNZuM6IW5uVA/IMG_2343+2.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/532edadde4b0dca092999646/1571766507841-V1B50OL23IYI8TI55EXO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCJXkbCY1jfz-S28OxEpex97gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UWsJH8Yw6GRI4XGuw0v0R875ZDN2AcCq2uvJM1Hx0IPwmjG7iZYqKSDNZuM6IW5uVA/IMG_2343+2.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="2186x2573" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMG_2343 2.jpeg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5daf40eb4f1c6b0ab853f212" data-type="image" />
          </div>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


<p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><br></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">Because it’s a camera, I can use it as a scanner and all that. But more excitingly, I can switch to it in video conferencing apps, and sketch my thoughts right in front of people. I’m finding it’s&nbsp;<strong>*really*really*good*</strong>&nbsp;to do this on video conference calls. Especially with software developers when you’re explaining just what you’d like them to build. I’m building something. I’ll tell you more next week.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><strong>Movements</strong></p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">I’m writing this at homebase in Brooklyn, but tomorrow I’m flying to London for work with Sainsbury’s, and the Friday I’m onto Bangkok where I am giving a keynote at the Digital Thailand Big Bang. My talk is called “Everything Silicon Valley Says About Innovation Is Wrong”.</p><p class="" style="white-space:pre-wrap;">I should pack. Thank you for your attention.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>224</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-22 17:48:59]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-22 17:48:59]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[2019-10-22-weeknotes-october-22]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="writing"><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>ReadyBrek, AR, and Flirting in the age of Corona</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/05/06/readybrek-ar-and-flirting-in-the-age-of-corona/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 14:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/?p=257</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"id":259,"width":611,"height":458,"sizeSlug":"large","className":"is-style-default"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized is-style-default"><img src="https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/images.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-259" width="611" height="458"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you grew up in the UK in the 1980s, you'll know this image. It's from a TV advert for a breakfast cereal called Ready Brek. It's porridge, but much more finely milled, so it's ready to eat as soon as you add the milk. It is unredeemingly grim, as are their adverts. I mean, I'm not saying that this part of my childhood is why I've spent most of my adulthood in Mediterranean climates, but watch this:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:core-embed/youtube {"url":"https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WzBxYi7IKzc","type":"video","providerNameSlug":"youtube","className":"wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WzBxYi7IKzc
</div></figure>
<!-- /wp:core-embed/youtube -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If this makes you nostaligic, you're insane.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Anyway, the red outline to the child, denoting a belly full of carbohydrate mush to fuel their way through the Thatcherite dystopia, is actually a pretty good bit of user interface when applied to the present day unpleasantness.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We know that Apple have AR glasses coming to market in the next year or so. <a href="https://www.slashgear.com/apple-ar-vr-headset-controller-test-device-leaked-26614522/">From this sort of reporting</a> and <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-11-11/apple-s-ar-push-will-start-with-ipad-and-culminate-with-glasses">this</a> and <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/04/04/apple-nextr-ar-headset/">this</a>. And despite the social nightmare of the forward facing camera that contributed to the Google Glass fiasco, AR glasses rely on forward facing sensors of some form. It'd be easy - trivial, in fact - to overlay a social distancing guide to your field of view. And maybe a bit trickier, but still thereabouts, for a forward facing IR camera to overlay anyone running an obvious fever with a ReadyBrek outline. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Apple, of course, have a patent for technology that would do this very thing<span id="fd37a3cd-9f52-45d1-957e-b9dd0490292c" data-note="One of the dark secrets of the Futurist trade is that people generally announce their plans well in advance. Whether in patent applications or political manifestos, most people are quite open about what they're going to do - even people who you might think would want to keep their Evil Plan secret. At a rough guess, 99.5% of all punditry is just special pleading around this: &quot;Surely they won't do what they're plainly said they will?&quot; Yes, yes they will." contenteditable="false" class="abt-footnote"><sup>​*​</sup></span>. <a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/WO2019067650A1/">https://patents.google.com/patent/WO2019067650A1/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The social practices that might come from exposing feverishness without contact, or from actually giving a genuine measure of the six-foot social distancing radius, are interesting to consider. After it becomes a matter of etiquette and good social graces to keep a distance, the violation of that boundary can be either an act of extreme aggression, or one of subtle intimacy: the <em>On peut se&nbsp;tutoyer</em> of public space. Or perhaps something more flirtatious. After all, fans, which given the unpleasantness of wearing a facemask in the summer, are due a comeback, <a href="https://www.nts.org.uk/stories/let-the-fan-do-the-talking-victorian-flirting-tips">have a long tradition of signaling and seductive language.</a> Tiny breaches of the 6 foot boundary will take on their own greater meanings, while the unveiling of the lower half of the face becomes the most private of moments.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":264,"width":610,"height":458,"sizeSlug":"large","className":"is-style-default"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized is-style-default"><img src="https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/4.Victorian_Fan_etiquette_from_the_Cassells_Family_Magazine_1866.23.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-264" width="610" height="458"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:abt/footnotes -->
<section aria-label="Footnotes" class="wp-block-abt-footnotes abt-footnotes" role="region"><hr/><ol><li class="abt-footnotes-item" id="fd37a3cd-9f52-45d1-957e-b9dd0490292c-ref"><div class="abt-footnotes-item__marker"><sup>​*​</sup></div><div class="abt-footnotes-item__content">One of the dark secrets of the Futurist trade is that people generally announce their plans well in advance. Whether in patent applications or political manifestos, most people are quite open about what they're going to do - even people who you might think would want to keep their Evil Plan secret. At a rough guess, 99.5% of all punditry is just special pleading around this: "Surely they won't do what they're plainly said they will?" Yes, yes they will.</div></li></ol></section>
<!-- /wp:abt/footnotes -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>257</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-05-06 10:31:40]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-06 14:31:40]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[readybrek-ar-and-flirting-in-the-age-of-corona]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="augmentation"><![CDATA[Augmentation]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="futures"><![CDATA[Futures]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="wearables"><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="writing"><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_abt_state]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{"references":[],"style":{"kind":"predefined","value":"apa-old-doi-prefix","label":"American Psychological Association 6th edition (\"doi:\" DOI prefix)","shortTitle":"APA"}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_b2s_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:8:"og_title";s:48:"ReadyBrek, AR, and Flirting in the age of Corona";s:7:"og_desc";s:160:"If you grew up in the UK in the 1980s, you'll know this image. It's from a TV advert for a breakfast cereal called Ready Brek. It's porridge, but much more fine";s:8:"og_image";s:64:"https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/images.jpeg";s:10:"card_title";s:48:"ReadyBrek, AR, and Flirting in the age of Corona";s:9:"card_desc";s:160:"If you grew up in the UK in the 1980s, you'll know this image. It's from a TV advert for a breakfast cereal called Ready Brek. It's porridge, but much more fine";s:10:"card_image";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_a4c2d64358a8c1547ab00f5874846b95]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<iframe title="Ready Brek &#039;Central Heating for Kids&#039; 30sec TV Ad." width="580" height="435" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WzBxYi7IKzc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_a4c2d64358a8c1547ab00f5874846b95]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1591105445]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>New Event - Leading in Times of Uncertainty</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/05/08/new-event-leading-in-times-of-uncertainty/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 16:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/?p=293</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I'm very happy to be speaking at the <a href="https://esbvirtualsummit.com">Executive Speakers Bureau virtual summit.</a> on May 20th. I'll be talking about "The Great Reassessment" - scenarios and planning for the post-Covid future.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":295,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/EXWK4A8U0AAchPq.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-295"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>293</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-05-08 12:59:13]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-08 16:59:13]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[new-event-leading-in-times-of-uncertainty]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="ben-hammersley"><![CDATA[Ben Hammersley]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="live-events"><![CDATA[Live Events]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_abt_state]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{"references":[],"style":{"kind":"predefined","value":"apa-old-doi-prefix","label":"American Psychological Association 6th edition (\"doi:\" DOI prefix)","shortTitle":"APA"}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_b2s_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:8:"og_title";s:43:"New Event - Leading in Times of Uncertainty";s:7:"og_desc";s:170:"I'm very happy to be speaking at the Executive Speakers Bureau virtual summit. on May 20th. I'll be talking about &quot;The Great Reassessment&quot; - scenarios and plann";s:8:"og_image";s:73:"https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/EXWK4A8U0AAchPq.jpeg";s:10:"card_title";s:43:"New Event - Leading in Times of Uncertainty";s:9:"card_desc";s:160:"I'm very happy to be speaking at the Executive Speakers Bureau virtual summit. on May 20th. I'll be talking about "The Great Reassessment" - scenarios and plann";s:10:"card_image";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Screens. Lots of screens.</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/05/09/screens-lots-of-screens/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 22:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/?p=300</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I've wanted to be able to do this for a long time, and now we can. Here's a video of my screen a minute or so ago<span id="eb20d77b-e858-49ce-8190-688d9c0bd679" data-note="Extra points to the people/cult members who spot the other thing hanging out in this video, and know of its brilliance. Because *damn* it's good." contenteditable="false" class="abt-footnote"><sup>​*​</sup></span>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:video {"guid":"NyyemXi6","id":302,"src":"https://benhammersley.com/immersed-quest-20200509-180409-mp4/"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-video wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-videopress"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://videopress.com/v/NyyemXi6?preloadContent=metadata
</div></figure>
<!-- /wp:video -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you have an <a href="https://www.oculus.com/quest">Oculus Quest</a>, and install the <a href="https://immersedvr.com">Immersed</a> app you can put your mac's displays into a VR world, and <em>then add more virtual monitors</em>, and place them in space around you. This is slight bonkers. But not as bonkers as the fact that you can still use Zoom.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":305,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Immersed.quest-20200509-182151.jpg?fit=580%2C580&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-305"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But then again, Immersed <a href="https://blog.immersed.team/co-work-in-a-virtual-coffee-shop-with-real-people-f220cef3d9b9">also lets you put yourself into a shared VR co-working space</a>. So, you know, move that one from the future column over to the present day. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:abt/footnotes -->
<section aria-label="Footnotes" class="wp-block-abt-footnotes abt-footnotes" role="region"><hr/><ol><li class="abt-footnotes-item" id="eb20d77b-e858-49ce-8190-688d9c0bd679-ref"><div class="abt-footnotes-item__marker"><sup>​*​</sup></div><div class="abt-footnotes-item__content">Extra points to the people/cult members who spot the other thing hanging out in this video, and know of its brilliance. Because *damn* it's good.</div></li></ol></section>
<!-- /wp:abt/footnotes -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>300</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-05-09 18:32:34]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-09 22:32:34]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[screens-lots-of-screens]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="augmentation"><![CDATA[Augmentation]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="futures"><![CDATA[Futures]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="wearables"><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_abt_state]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{"references":[],"style":{"kind":"predefined","value":"apa-old-doi-prefix","label":"American Psychological Association 6th edition (\"doi:\" DOI prefix)","shortTitle":"APA"}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_d985eafa511b0c4beac8fbe234d74de8]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<iframe title="immersed-quest-20200509-180409-mp4" width='580' height='580' src='https://videopress.com/embed/NyyemXi6?preloadContent=metadata&amp;hd=0' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><script src='https://v0.wordpress.com/js/next/videopress-iframe.js?m=1435166243'></script>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_d985eafa511b0c4beac8fbe234d74de8]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1589062825]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_b2s_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:10:"card_title";s:25:"Screens. Lots of screens.";s:9:"card_desc";s:155:"I've wanted to be able to do this for a long time, and now we can. Here's a video of my screen a minute or so ago​*​.https://videopress.com/v/NyyemXi6?";s:10:"card_image";s:120:"https://i1.wp.com/benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Immersed.quest-20200509-182151.jpg?fit=580,580&#038;ssl=1";s:8:"og_title";s:25:"Screens. Lots of screens.";s:7:"og_desc";s:155:"I've wanted to be able to do this for a long time, and now we can. Here's a video of my screen a minute or so ago​*​.https://videopress.com/v/NyyemXi6?";s:8:"og_image";s:122:"https://i1.wp.com/benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Immersed.quest-20200509-182151.jpg?fit=580%2C580&#038;ssl=1";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Burner Devices, Bunny Suits, Biosecurity Clauses, and Blood Work</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/05/13/burner-devices-bunny-suits-biosecurity-clauses-and-blood-work/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 20:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/?p=312</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Up until February, I averaged 30 countries a year<span id="9799c11b-dc6d-4e06-b24a-5ea6d520844c" data-note="All trips aggressively carbon-offset I assure you." contenteditable="false" class="abt-footnote"><sup>​*​</sup></span>. Some for 24 hours, some for a week, but either way, my work ordinarily takes me all over the world. With the lockdown, of course, all of that has been put on pause, and like most other people who work with ideas for a living, I'm typing and Zooming and pivoting my existing work and future contracts into new biosecure shapes. And so, like everyone else, I'm planning for an interesting future. It's clear that the digitization and post-geographisation of the consulting and advisory world has been hugely accelerated, and I think it's also clear that it's not going to go back to the old normal either. For sure, there is a considerable power in the sort of in-person meeting I would ordinarily do - whether in front of a single CEO, a 20 person board, or a 5000 person theatre - but that's not always going to be enough to, you know, ask people to possibly die for. And by the time the vaccines are ready and working, the cultures of business meetings will have changed.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But what of that change? What do business meetings look like in a world that has experienced a pandemic? It's a useful exercise to work through, because many of the same concepts are equally as relevant when we're considering the mitigation of other vectored risks: cybercrime, for example, or industrial espionage.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":314,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img src="https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Unknown-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-314"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Here's what I'm thinking: Burner Devices, Bunny Suits, Biosecurity Clauses, and Blood Work. Ignoring for the moment the two-week quarantine that some countries are haphazardly imposing on some inbound travelers (because those will certainly go away sooner rather than later), it will most likely come down to individual companies to enforce their own particular rules. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":318,"sizeSlug":"large","className":"is-style-default"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image is-style-default"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img src="https://benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/crop-0-0-186-271-0-images-2.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-318"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Being granted access to a location-based headquarters, rather than just given a login to a virtual workplace, will depend on your own person being sufficiently and provably biosecure: blood test results showing a positive result for antigens, and a warm-zone changing area to put on tyvek PPE. Not to protect yourself, but to shield the staff community from your own personal viral shedding. Devices are filthy already, both microbiologically and with malware, so those can't come in. If you need a screen to operate, you'll get a blanked device to access the cloud with, VPN'd only, and isolated from the rest of the building. Masks, sure, or maybe the customer greeting rooms will be negatively pressured, and airlocked from the main building. Not just for Corona virus, or whatever the next one is, but for common flu and noro and all the other things we're now also mitigating while we work to avoid Covid19.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":316,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/94-iphones-strapped-china.jpg?fit=580%2C386&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-316"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But perhaps the most like is the biosecurity clause. And this goes both ways: the right to pause, or cancel, a contract if one party believes the other to be endangering biosecurity. If I'm due to visit a client in their clean-room meeting facility, and I turn up and find no one is wearing a mask and that dude in the corner is coughing suspiciously, can I contract the right to walk away without loss? Or can my client enforce the reverse, where I arrive from Brooklyn, attempting to smuggle in some fomites and looking feverish? </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"textColor":"accent"} -->
<p class="has-accent-color has-text-color">UPDATE: The doyenne of workplace design, Alex Deschamps-Sonsino, <a href="https://twitter.com/iotwatch/status/1260949958771032065?s=20">has a great thread about post-Covid offices here</a>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:abt/footnotes -->
<section aria-label="Footnotes" class="wp-block-abt-footnotes abt-footnotes" role="region"><hr/><ol><li class="abt-footnotes-item" id="9799c11b-dc6d-4e06-b24a-5ea6d520844c-ref"><div class="abt-footnotes-item__marker"><sup>​*​</sup></div><div class="abt-footnotes-item__content">All trips aggressively carbon-offset I assure you.</div></li></ol></section>
<!-- /wp:abt/footnotes -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>312</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-05-13 16:06:11]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-13 20:06:11]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[burner-devices-bunny-suits-biosecurity-clauses-and-blood-work]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="futures"><![CDATA[Futures]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_abt_state]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{"references":[],"style":{"kind":"predefined","value":"apa-old-doi-prefix","label":"American Psychological Association 6th edition (\"doi:\" DOI prefix)","shortTitle":"APA"}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_b2s_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:8:"og_title";s:64:"Burner Devices, Bunny Suits, Biosecurity Clauses, and Blood Work";s:7:"og_desc";s:160:"Up until February, I averaged 30 countries a year​*​. Some for 24 hours, some for a week, but either way, my work ordinarily takes me all over the world. Wi";s:8:"og_image";s:0:"";s:10:"card_title";s:64:"Burner Devices, Bunny Suits, Biosecurity Clauses, and Blood Work";s:9:"card_desc";s:160:"Up until February, I averaged 30 countries a year​*​. Some for 24 hours, some for a week, but either way, my work ordinarily takes me all over the world. Wi";s:10:"card_image";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Liked Links - May 18</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/05/18/liked-links-may-18/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 23:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/?p=324</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Map of Bay Area Memespace</strong>: The Bay Area is unusually dense with idea-driven subcultures that mix and cross-pollinate in fascinating ways, many of which are already enriching rationalist culture. This map is my attempt at illustrating that landscape of subcultures, and at situating the rationalist community within it. - by Julia Galef - <a href="https://juliagalef.com/2017/02/20/map-of-bay-area-memespace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://juliagalef.com/2017/02/20/map-of-bay-area-memespace/</a>

<strong>Agathonic things</strong>: Though mediocrity is ubiquitous, among all the dross there are objects which improve with use—so-called agathonic things. Michael Helms and Larry Leifer proposed the idea of agathonic design in 2009. - <a href="https://vaughntan.org/agathonic-things" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://vaughntan.org/agathonic-things</a>

<strong>Edward Said's </strong>: Edward Said, a Palestinan writer, academic and exile, talks about his book "Culture and Imperialism" and explains how the attitudes forged over the last 200 years continue to enforce the relationship between the west and the developing world.

This programme originally aired in February 1993.

T - by Eqbal Ahmad FB Fan Page Admin - <a href="https://vimeo.com/414226354" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://vimeo.com/414226354</a>

<strong>ADHD Needs a Better Name. We Have One.</strong>: ADHD is not purely a disorder; it is a mix of assets and liabilities. A more representative name for the condition is VAST, or variable attention stimulus trait. - by Edward Hallowell - <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/attention-deficit-disorder-vast/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.additudemag.com/attention-deficit-disorder-vast/</a>

<strong>Weber–Fechner law</strong>: The Weber–Fechner law refers to two related hypotheses in the field of psychophysics, known as Weber's law and Fechner's law. Both laws relate to human perception, more specifically the relation between the actual change in a physical stimulus and the perceived change. - by From Wikipedia, the free - <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weber%E2%80%93Fechner_law" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weber%E2%80%93Fechner_law</a>

<strong>The early days of home computing – in pictures</strong>: A new book documents the rapid evolution in home computer design - by Kadish Morris - <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/gallery/2020/apr/11/the-early-days-of-home-computing-in-pictures" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.theguardian.com/technology/gallery/2020/apr/11/the-early-days-of-home-computing-in-pictures</a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>324</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-05-18 23:42:46]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-05-18 23:42:46]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[close]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[liked-links-may-18]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="links"><![CDATA[Links]]></category>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-link"><![CDATA[Link]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_abt_state]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{"references":[],"style":{"kind":"predefined","value":"apa-old-doi-prefix","label":"American Psychological Association 6th edition (\"doi:\" DOI prefix)","shortTitle":"APA"}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_b2s_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:8:"og_title";s:20:"Liked Links - May 18";s:7:"og_desc";s:160:"Map of Bay Area Memespace: The Bay Area is unusually dense with idea-driven subcultures that mix and cross-pollinate in fascinating ways, many of which are alre";s:8:"og_image";s:0:"";s:10:"card_title";s:20:"Liked Links - May 18";s:9:"card_desc";s:160:"Map of Bay Area Memespace: The Bay Area is unusually dense with idea-driven subcultures that mix and cross-pollinate in fascinating ways, many of which are alre";s:10:"card_image";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Brooklyn Protests</title>
		<link>https://benhammersley.com/2020/06/04/brooklyn-protests/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 20:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dangerousprecedent]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benhammersley.com/?p=340</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Back in the early 2000s I used to like to go to hot places and take pictures. I don't really do that any more, and my trusty EOS1DSMk2 has been sat uncharged for years. I got it out again this morning, and just got back from the memorial protest for George Floyd. It's 4pm on Thursday June 4th 2020, and here's some history for the future to see.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":341,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/X6D6421.jpeg?fit=580%2C870&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-341"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":342,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/X6D6422.jpeg?fit=580%2C387&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-342"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":343,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/X6D6415.jpeg?fit=580%2C870&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-343"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":344,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/benhammersley.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/X6D6390.jpeg?fit=580%2C387&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-344"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>340</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-06-04 16:10:13]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-06-04 20:10:13]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[brooklyn-protests]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="writing"><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[medium_post]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:11:"Medium_Post":11:{s:16:"author_image_url";N;s:10:"author_url";N;s:11:"byline_name";N;s:12:"byline_email";N;s:10:"cross_link";N;s:2:"id";N;s:21:"follower_notification";N;s:7:"license";N;s:14:"publication_id";N;s:6:"status";N;s:3:"url";N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_abt_state]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{"references":[],"style":{"kind":"predefined","value":"apa-old-doi-prefix","label":"American Psychological Association 6th edition (\"doi:\" DOI prefix)","shortTitle":"APA"}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_pingme]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_b2s_post_meta]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:8:"og_title";s:17:"Brooklyn Protests";s:7:"og_desc";s:160:"Back in the early 2000s I used to like to go to hot places and take pictures. I don't really do that any more, and my trusty EOS1DSMk2 has been sat uncharged fo";s:8:"og_image";s:0:"";s:10:"card_title";s:17:"Brooklyn Protests";s:9:"card_desc";s:160:"Back in the early 2000s I used to like to go to hot places and take pictures. I don't really do that any more, and my trusty EOS1DSMk2 has been sat uncharged fo";s:10:"card_image";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>
	